Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
Woah
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
nezumiiro no sora no shita
Higawari no chizu
ikutsumo no yume ga nijinde ita
Itsuka wa sa chippoke na
boku no kono hohaba demo
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
Tsuyogatte kizutsuita kokoro sukashita you ni
Furidashita amatsubutachi ga
ranhansha kurikaesu
Massugu na hikari ga kousa shite
Yukusaki mo tsugenu mama
dokomademo tsukinukeru
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakistukete
Kono sora no shita donna toko ni ite mo
Todoku hazu nanda mada minu sekai e
[DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
Oh no, not again.
We've told you, you're an
important candidate for sacrifice.
We need you to keep your strength up.
Understand?
So, dig in, Dr. Marcoh.
You know what?
I've been sitting here a while.
Trying to decide what
you mean by sacrifice.
Trying to figure out why I'm here,
and what it is exactly you want me to do.
I'm fairly certain that what
you're doing right now is using
this land and its people to
form a giant transmutation circle.
And your hope is that
the end result will be the
creation of a Philosopher's Stone.
Am I wrong?
So close. Not quite.
But you're on the right track.
Then what is it?
The question is, are you going
to cooperate with us or not?
If not, the village is history.
[GASP]
Lust told me about your arrangement.
If we agree to leave the village
alone, then you'll do whatever we ask.
[WHIMPERING]
Which is it? Agree to work with
us and kill everyone in this country?
Or refuse to work with us and watch
everyone in your beloved village die?
Fool. You just have to forsake one
little village to save an entire country.
Too bad you don't have the
stomach to do the logical thing.
I shouldn't be surprised.
That's just how all you humans are.
You put emotions before common sense.
I killed a man who was like that once.
All I had to do was make myself
look like his wife and he was helpless,
He couldn't even fight me.
Humans are so easy to take advantage of.
Lucky us.
The humans seem to be giving you quite
a bit of trouble lately, don't they, Wrath?
Hmm?
First Scar gets away from you,
then those others make off with Gluttony.
It's not like you.
Yes, you are right about that.
And yet you seem happy.
Yes, I won't deny it.
This has been... enjoyable.
I've been alive for 60 years and now here
I am in the ultimate position of power.
All has gone exactly as
father had planned it would.
There's more, though.
Roy Mustang and his underlings,
the enterprising Elric brothers,
and these foreigners
who suddenly appeared from Xing.
As good as we are,
they've still got us scrambling in circles.
Things are changing.
The time may be approaching
when we have to move over
for the younger generation.
Don't you see?
Listen to yourself, Wrath. You've been
around these humans for far too long.
You may be right, Pride.
I hope you will stop this foolishness and
remember who we are and what we must do.
I won't tell father
what you've said tonight.
He might be inclined
to see it as treason.
Anyway, about Gluttony...
Don't worry about that.
I have access to military information, after all.
I know where he is.
What was that?
Colonel! What's going on?
Hawkeye, stop!
Colonel!
Lieutenant!
Don't provoke him! I'm the one he wants!
Mustang!
Come on. We're getting out of here.
What is it? What's happening?
The Homunculus. He had another
monster hidden inside his belly.
He's swallowing up everything in sight!
Alchemy can produce something like that...
How disgusting!
Let's go. We have to bring him down.
But we worked so hard to
catch one of the Homunculi!
Survival is our first priority.
Besides, he knows our names and faces now.
It would be foolish to
let him leave here alive.
[BURPS]
He swallowed it?
Uh-oh.
Hey, that worked well!
Think you can do better? Be my guest!
Or we can just leave you behind, Colonel!
You're the one he really wants!
Those trees over there! Spread out!
Damn it! Not now!
Hurry up and get in the car!
Come on! We haven't got all night!
We need to get moving!
No way! I'm a civilian, not military!
I'm not about to die in the middle of
a battle with some crazed monster!
Damn it!
What's taking those idiots so long?
Mustang!
[ROARS]
No!
Perfect. He fell for the Mustang decoy.
Doesn't sound like
he's very happy about it.
All right. Now get in the car, invalid.
Lieutenant, please take care of Lan Fan.
You expect me to run away
and leave this to you, Elric?
If you stay, you'll just get in our way!
Yeah, leave!
They're right.
You won't be any use here. Sorry.
How did this idiot make Colonel?
Right now you need to go and do your job.
The head of the military
is a Homunculus.
Don't you think you should
do something about that?
The head of the military?
You aren't talking about
Fuhrer Bradley, are you?
We can talk about it later. Now get in!
The car looks full. You go ahead.
You dumbasses!
You can't really believe we'll let a couple
of children fight this battle for us!
With the senior staff involved in this,
you're gonna need all the help you can get.
And that would include
getting whatever information
we can out of this Gluttony
guy, wouldn't you say?
We'll stay here and find out what we can.
I don't think it matters
much that we're children.
This was our mission to begin with,
and we're going to see it through.
We appreciate your
help up till now, though.
- Here, Edward.
- Hmm?
I want you to take this.
You do know how to use it, don't you?
That's a weapon. For killing people.
Yes, but it's also a weapon
for protecting your lives.
It's your hands...
They weren't meant to kill.
No dying, okay?
I'll take it.
[CRASH]
[GASPS]
Look after Lan Fan.
Wait! My lord!
Let's go.
I said go!
Damn! What are they thinking?
Those three are gonna get themselves killed!
Mustang...
Where are you, Mustang?
You killed Lust! You will pay!
Well, said we'd stay and all,
but that's seriously freaky!
He seems to be a bit angry.
How are we gonna catch him?
What was that?
A dog?
Stop it! Now, gluttony!
A talking dog?
Hey, long time no see.
How are ya, Fullmetal Pipsqueak?
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Damn it! I told you before!
Don't call me short!
Hey, calm down! I'm just here to get
Gluttony back. Nothing more than that.
- I don't wanna fight you, Pipsqueak!
- That's five, now!
What are you talking about?
Five times!
You called me Pipsqueak twice here!
And three times in the laboratory!
Don't tell me you've forgotten already!
Impressive.
You've got a sharp memory there.
Hold it!
You're becoming bothersome.
Mustang was here! Must avenge Lust!
Swallow! Swallow!
Swallow him up!
You don't get the Colonel.
Or the Elric brothers.
Why not?
I've sensed this multiplicity before.
How many people are inside you, Homunculus?
I know you. You're the kid who
crossed swords with Wrath, aren't you?
What do you mean, kid? I happen to
be the twelfth son of the Emperor of Xing!
- My name is—
- Eat him!
No! No! No! No! No! No! No! No!
You thinking what I'm thinking?
Looks like they really aren't allowed
to do anything to the two of us.
[CHUCKLES] In which case...
Ling! You get that one!
Very well. Let's see how good you are.
You held off Wrath, but
how will you do against me?
Oh? Did he now?
Yes. It was the best paper in the class.
He chose to write an
essay all about you, actually.
Mom, can I read it to you guys now?
Not at the table. Mind your manners, dear.
Oh, don't be silly. Why not?
Go ahead and read, son.
I'd like to hear it.
Great!
Essay on my dad.
He's the Führer of the nation of Amestris.
He works hard all the time, and
everything he does is for our country.
The people of Amestris
are always in his heart.
He dedicates his life to making them happy.
He deals with all sorts
of problems each day,
so everyone in our
country can live a good life.
But no matter how busy he gets doing
his job, my dad never forgets his family.
He loves me and my mother very much.
He always looks out for us.
My dad's a good man.
He always listens to me when I talk to him.
He's always kind and protects our family.
And that is why...
I love my dad. The end.
Thank you for that, Selim. Very much.
You really know how to use that thing.
Thank you for the compliment.
Really!
You fell for it.
Good, isn't it?
And you humans can't do anything like it.
So what'll it be?
Strangled to death?
Beaten to death?
Or just carved up into little pieces?
[LAUGHS] None of the above.
That was a dirty trick.
Blinding me, that's not playing fair.
People have been trying to
assassinate me since I was a kid.
Under the circumstances, you can't blame
a guy for learning how to fight dirty.
So, have you had enough yet?
Are you going to come with me quietly now?
I just want whatever information you
can give me on becoming immortal.
Or shall we go again?
You scum!
A mere human like you
can't condescend to me!
You seem to underestimate humans.
And that's a mistake!
Nice! Got him!
That was a close one.
I've had enough of you!
Get away! I can't eat you!
Just let me take a bite
from the other guy!
Not today!
Stay out of my way, guys. I'm busy.
[GASP]
Another foolish human.
Go for it, Gluttony!
Ling!
What?
Damn it! I can't let him eat a sacrifice!
Brother!
[GASP]
Swallowed them?
Brother!
Wing!
You! Spit them out!
Spit them out now!
I can't.
I swallowed them.
[GASP]
Impossible.
It can't be.
Brother...
[SCREAMS]
I do have another room
that my kid used to sleep in.
But people will get suspicious
if I keep all the lights on.
You'll have to make do with my bed.
My lord, I have to go to him.
Idiot girl!
What can you do in your condition?
He isn't home yet?
I see.
I'll head straight to the
command center then.
Right.
Goodbye.
- Let's go.
-Right.
Go where?
I think now would be a good time to find
out who we can trust and who we can't.
What is it with you idiots?
You got a death wish?
Your wounds haven't
begun to heal yet and you're already
going out, looking for more trouble?
For all we know, the
Fuhrer is a Homunculus.
I can't very well ignore that.
Besides, we just left children out
on a battlefield to do our fighting.
If they're brave enough to fight,
how can I just sit here and wait?
What's so funny?
Oh, it's nothing really,
I was just thinking.
Can you imagine the look on Edward's
face if he heard you talking back there?
I was only repeating what you already said.
I have to admit, this is unexpected.
Given the situation, this is fairly
bold action for you to take, Colonel.
Like hell it is.
I'm just getting the ball
rolling, nothing more.
Besides...
You need as many people on your side
as you can get your hands on now, Colonel.
It's taken long enough, but I think I
might finally begin heeding his advice.
These are either the gates to
glory or the entranceway to hell.
Wait here, Lieutenant.
If anything happens to me, then at least
you'll have a chance of getting out alive.
No, sir.
That was an order.
One that I cannot obey.
You're a stubborn one.
That's something you've always known, sir.
[SIGHS]
All right.
Will you stay here if I
promise to come back?
Yes.
Happy hunting, sir.
So you're Colonel Roy Mustang, are you?
I got a call from my wife
about you a while ago.
Lieutenant General Raven, I'm sorry.
I haven't had time to introduce myself.
I've been very busy since my transfer.
It's not a problem.
Tell me, how is that old fox
Grumman doing these days anyway?
[CHUCKLES] The same as always, sir.
Check!
That's eleven losses in a row for me.
Twelve, actually.
But at least you put up a
decent fight this time around.
You were fine until you were
sure you'd won, then you blew it.
So I finished too weak?
Yes.
You can't be ruthless enough.
You're a lot like Raven that way.
Lieutenant General Raven?
From Central?
He's an exceptional
soldier, but too sentimental.
From what I've heard, he'll even
tend to his wounded men himself,
which leaves his whole
line of command in disarray.
You don't deploy your king
to tend to the pawns, do you?
How dare he say
something like that about me!
I was transferred to
Central because of the
compassion I showed
my men in the line of duty!
That border-dwelling old
coot should keep his trap shut!
Sorry.
No, General, it's fine.
Actually, General Grumman told
me that if that story made you angry,
it meant you were still a good and just
man, and that you were the officer one could
come to for support in
case of an emergency.
I can't believe it.
That old fox got me again, didn't he?
[CHUCKLES]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
It's time for my meeting.
Come on, you can walk with me.
Have you adjusted to Central yet?
No.
I find conversing with the citizens
around here quite difficult, actually.
It's a mistake to dismiss the value
of the word on the street, Colonel.
I know.
But most of it's just mindless drivel.
Like, "Scar was seen feeding a stray cat" or, "immortality has been discovered".
Or maybe even that Fuhrer
Bradley is a Homunculus.
Who knows?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
I see, you've got no
sense of humor, do you?
Are you certain you were
one of Grumman's men?
His sense of humor didn't
rub off on me much, sir.
Well, at least that bit of gossip will
give us something to talk about over tea.
Huh?
I-I couldn't possibly
attend something like...
Go on, tell your little joke.
You know, the one about the
Fuhrer being a Homunculus.
Please, go ahead.
What, Colonel Mustang?
Cat got your tongue?
Let's suppose for a moment that I
was actually a Homunculus, as you say.
Well now, would that be so bad?
Ah, I understand now, Hughes.
When you said that we were in trouble,
you didn't mean the
danger was closing in on us.
No, you meant the
danger was coming from us.
Well, Fullmetal, it looks like we've
landed ourselves in the pit of hell.
Where am I?
Blood?
What the?!
What is this place?
Al?
Hey!
Is anybody out there?
Where the hell am I?
Let it all out, let it all out
Tsuyogaranakute ii n da ne
Dareka ga kaite'tta
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
Jibunrashisa nante, dare mo wakaranai yo
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu
de nakushitari, hirottari,
Kyuu ni samishiku natte,
naichau hi mo aru kedo
Namida mo itami mo, hoshi ni kaeyou
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
Chiisana te kazashite
futari de tsukurou hoshikuzu wo
Tsuyoku hikaru ein wo
Sayonara itsuka wa kuru ka mo shirenu
Kisetsu wa sore demo meguri megutte'ku
Chiisaku mayotte mo aruite'ku
Kimi to aruite'ku
Sore daku wa kawaranaide iyou ne
Do you feel driven to keep searching for someone
who is lost, because you fear to be left alone,
or because you have no choice?
Because even if you cannot see them,
you cannot believe they are gone.
Next time on Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 25: Doorway of Darkness
The fight continues inside the belly of the beast.